### Eiman Alsakha

14 Park ave, Glen Cove New York, 11542 516-502-5916 www.eimanalsakha.com

Dear Sir/ Madam at Ineco,

I'm writing in hopes to meet with you and discuss a job opportunity when I visit Spain in September, 2014. I'm considering moving to Spain and would like to meet with enthusiastic architects and urban planners who have gained Global recognition.

I have been practicing architecture and urban design in the New York metropolitan area for the past three years or so. Throughout my education and career, I gained the skills to work at multiple scales and with different teams. I became cognizant of architecture, urban and suburban systems, landscape architecture, and I became aware of the importance of good work-live settings in homes and cities. I also participated in some design competitions such as the Material Recovery Center in Nosara, Costa Rica. My team won an honorable mention prize and traveled to Costa Rica to meet with the client and start construction.

Currently, I'm involved with all phases of project development for international hospitality projects in South America and Jamaica. Most of these international projects require high sensitivity to culture and spatial analysis. I'm also involved in the design development of local institutional, residential and educational projects. Besides my demanding everyday job requirements, I'm always on the look for new clients to introduce to my current work environment. I also try to stay involved in community minded projects such as El puente Mobile wellness Cart in NYC and the ongoing fund raising to finish an ICT center in Ghana. Also, for the past two years, I have been invited as a design guest critic at New York Institute of Technology and Columbia University. I'm hard-working and willing to ask questions and learn new things.

I appreciate Ineco's diverse and multidisciplinary work. Your constant search and your systematic approach makes you a very desirable place for me as an enthusiastic designer. I'm extremely fond of the innovation in infrastructure that Ineco has offered to cities all over the world. I became especially aware of Ineco since it is working on the Haramain High Speed Train project in my home country Saudi Arabia. My knowledge about that region of the world might be of a good addition to your ongoing projects. I see myself growing in an environment that encourages learning, teaching, researching, and enhancing public realms. This puts Ineco at a very respectful level. I would be very proud to be a part of your innovative and cutting edge team.

Yours,

Eiman Alsakha

Eiman A Sakha Eiman Alsakha 14 Park Ave, Glen Cove, NY, 11542

Cell: 516-502-5916

E-mail: eiman.alsakha@gmail.com Web: http://www.eimanalsakha.com

#### **EDUCATION**

- Columbia University, New York

Master of Science in Architecture & Urban Design, (May, 2013)

- New York Institute of Technology, Old Westbury

Bachelor of Architecture (May, 2012)

GPA 3.92

Education financed through a scholarship

## **STUDY ABROAD**

- Kumasi urban design trip, (February, 2013)

Participated in the Columbia University's urban design studio III trip to Ghana.

- S-lab Costa Rica, Costa Rica (January, 2012)

Participated in a design-built initiative to design a recycling center for Nosara, Costa Rica

- Peru community service trip (March, 2012)

Took a part in a community service trip organized by NYIT in partnership with the YMCA, Peru to help communities in Lima & Independencia. Participated in the labor construction of a pharmacy.

- Potsdam workshop, Germany (Fall, 2010)

Participated in a team work to re-design the Potsdam Women's Soccer Club.

- Ricardo Porro's Studio, Paris, (Spring, 2010)

Design 6 Porro's Studio trip, sponsored by NYIT.

- Design fundamentals, Bahrain (Winter- Spring, 2006) Studied design fundamentals at NYIT, Bahrain campus.

- English studies at Centre Linguista, Montreal (Summer, 2005)

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

- Urban Designer/Planner - Eduardo Lacroze AIA Architect, Long Island, NY (June 2013- Current)

Involved with all phases of project development for international Hospitality industry projects in markets where the firm has been active, namely Latin America (currently Chile ,Peru , Colombia & Panama) and Northwest Africa.

Architectural design and design development in local institutional & educational projects with campus/ community involvement (community centers, school facilities, plazas)

- Design Member - El Puente's Mobile Wellness Unit, NYC (Fall 2013) Design & Fund Collection Phase

Participated in forming urban ideas for the mobile unit.

Produced diagrams and rendered images for fund collection and community meetings.

- Outreach committee member Center for Architecture, NYC (Fall 2012)
- Junior Architect Assistant George Hillenbrand Assoc., NYC (May 2011- May 2012)

Produced plans, sections, elevations and rendered images. Created sample and presentation boards for clients.

Field experience including measuring existing conditions in

residential and commercial spaces.

Trained upcoming replacement employees.

- Graphic designer- New York Institute of Technology (Spring, 2011) Created layouts for students' work for the 2011 NAAB exhibit. - Peer Advisor- New York Institute of Technology (Fall, 2010)

Helped freshmen architecture students to understand the school's program and policies.

Gave academic help and moral support to students.

Helped generating schedules and graduation plans to freshmen and transfer students.

- Wall Artist- Al Qatif National Kindergarten, Qatif, K.S.A. (2006)

Classroom wall artist.

Designed classrooms' play sections.

Assisted in designing plays' costumes.

- Active Artist- Atelier Fan "Art Gallery of Hameeda Alsinan", Qatif, K.S.A. (2003-2006) Assisted in relations coordination.

Exhibit curator.

Active artist and member of the atelier.

# **AWARDS/ HONORS**

- Golden Key member
- Phi Eta Sigma member
- Dean's list at NYIT
- Tau Sigma Delta member
- A winner of the annual design 5 competition, NYIT, Freeport Studio, December, 2009
- AIAS member
- Honorable mention team of a design-build initiative- S-Lab Costa Rica, 2012
- Woman's History Month Honoree of 2012- Nominated by the Career Services Offices at NYIT
- Outstanding Community Service Award- 2012 NYIT
- Honorable mention for Movement on Main Competition-April 2013
- Urban design studio III Work presented at the Holcim Conference, 2013
- Kinne Fellows Traveling Prize- Columbia University, May, 2013

# **SOFTWARE KNOWLEDGE**

- Adobe (Photoshop, In-Design-Illustrator, After Effect)
- Autodesk (3Ds Max Studio, Auto Cad, Maya, Ecotect, Revit)
- Google Sketch Up
- Microsoft (Word, Power Point, Excel)
- Arc GIS

### **LANGUAGES**

- Arabic- Native Language
- English- Fluent in speaking, writing, and listening
- Spanish- Beginner

#### REFERENCES

Matthias Altwicker- Associate Professor|Dept Chair Undergraduate Thesis Advisor NYIT matthiasaltwicker@gmail.com 212.261.1628

Amy Bravo- Assistant Dean|Career Services NYIT Peru Trip Director abravo@nyit.edu 212.261.1538